Richard B. Carter

3500 E. McKinney St. APT 6202 Cell: (915) 886-8422

Denton, TX 76209 E-mail: carter502@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Pursue a career in web/software development, contributing growth to outstanding companies regardless of size.

OVERVIEW

I am a trustworthy, self-motivated individual with tremendous enthusiasm for helping others and dedication to making myself an asset. I am a combat veteran with 8 years served in the US Army. I am eager to serve and contribute growth to those in need. I have been recognized for my responsibility and leadership, successfully completing tasks on time, learning new skills quickly and applying them effectively.

EDUCATION

ElevenFifty Academy, front end web development bootcamp Currently attending

University of North Texas, *School of Journalism* (9/2015 – 12/2017) Completed 57 credits towards a Bachelor's degree in Public Relations.

Advanced Individual Training, US Army 4/2002-11/2002 14E (PATRIOT Missile System Operator Maintainer)

GED, 2001 Tennessee State University Nashville, TN

WORK EXPERIENCE

6/2019-8/2020 City of Denton Denton, TX

- Water Production, Operator I

Worked as Operator I in a water production plant. Earned Class D water license from Texas Commission on Environmental Quality (TCEQ), the state authority for licensing and regulation in the water industry. Responsible for assisting the Operator II on duty with keeping the water plant and distribution system in operation and within compliance. Collected various water and chemical samples to conduct tests, analyze, record and report for safety and compliance purposes. Tests for turbidity, chlorine, ammonia, chloramines, fluoride, ozone and others. Required handling hazardous chemicals at times and interacting with chemical delivery drivers to ensure proper loads arrived, chemical quality was acceptable and proper unloading procedures were followed. Also responsible for routine cleanliness and some minor maintenance repair work that did not need to be work ordered out to the maintenance department.

2/2019-6/2019 DoorDash Denton, TX

- Delivery Driver

Worked as an independent contractor delivering food and groceries with DoorDash. Required to make my own schedule and keep records of earnings, expenses and miles driven. I have maintained my driver approval rating within the highest possible category while holding a perfect record for orders accepted, delivered on time and completed. Daily experience interacting with customers and merchants, sometimes being proactive to resolve issues that occur with orders and deliveries. Regular preventive maintenance on my vehicle to ensure that my vehicle remains in good condition.

6/2010-4/2014 Tatitlek Corporation Fort Bliss, TX
Cubic Corporation McGregor Range, NM
Dona Ana Range Complex, NM

Range Operator/Maintainer

Responsible for the maintenance and operations of target mechanisms and range training aids used for weapon qualification and live fire exercises by military units, tower operations as range control. Primarily worked on convoy live fire ranges, with experience on small arms qualification ranges as well. Sometimes this included nonstandard range setups for infantry

maneuvers and Special Forces training as well, requiring a great deal of flexibility and subject matter expertise in an independent role.

Primary duties include programming target scenarios into remote control handhelds and tower facility-based Windows computer programs, emplacing and troubleshooting a variety of target mechanisms to correct malfunctions on the spot and for recurring use in support of ongoing training by various military units.

Additional duties include training units on the proper use of handheld controllers prior to their use of a range; along with briefing them on safety guidelines, range protocol, and proper range clearing procedures. This also required vigilant monitoring of personnel making proper use of personal protective equipment (PPE) for safety. Maintained professional appearance of the ranges, spot clearing vegetation, building target frames from various cuts of wood, building new ranges, assisting in large scale training exercises in remote areas (such as IRON FOCUS) with target setup and target maintenance; this included maintaining cleanliness and functionality of shop buildings, vehicles, and tools.

Required to perform maintenance periodically on roads decayed by weather and military track vehicles (tanks). Required to move around heavy stocks of supplies. Accomplished with informal use of Bobcat vehicles with attachments (to include limited experience with forklift), shovels, Auger drills, and water tanks mounted on trailers. Required to perform routine maintenance on electronic components. Common use of hand tools and equipment such as hammers, screwdrivers, wrenches, pliers, hand drills, auger drills, saws, multimeters, shovels, rakes, sledgehammers, axes, portable generators, and Bobcat vehicles.

11/2008 - 8/2009 Texas Army National Guard COB Adder, Tallil Air Base, Iraq

- Convoy Escort Team - Primary Gunner, Driver, and Truck Commander (TC)

Responsible for preventive maintenance checks, vehicle maintenance, weapon systems maintenance, communications (radio and satellite based), and communications security during a 10-month deployment to Iraq. As a member (gunner) of Convoy Commander's truck crew was collectively responsible for the security of 6 military vehicles, each with 3-4 man crews, and the support of 50-60 tractor trailer vehicles used for transporting supplies throughout Iraq.

Also served as scout vehicle gunner for large portion of deployment, where our crew was responsible for identifying threats well ahead of the main body of the convoy and taking necessary action to negate hostile threats. Doubled as scout vehicle driver as we would cross train and switch roles to avoid complacency or tiredness on long trips.

As a Truck Commander at the rank of E-4 (Specialist), I was responsible for a crew of equal and greater rank than myself in the primary casualty evacuation vehicle. I was recognized for my excellent service in this position and took on additional duties with ease. Tasked with primary

Blue Force Tracker duties and Assistant Convoy Commander duties, I was responsible for keeping full accountability of the convoy, maintaining communication with sector authority, unit tactical headquarters, other convoys, and reporting all events to higher authority as we traveled through Iraq in support of escorting supplies and personnel.

Logged over 12,000 miles through some of Iraq's most volatile routes; along Route Tampa and various auxiliary supply routes. Team was responsible for driving over 84,000 miles and transporting 15,000,000 lbs of supplies and 5,000,000 gallons of fuel supplies in support of operating forces in Iraq.

6/2008 - 10/2008 Texas Army National Guard Fort Stewart, GA

Trained more than 15 hours each day in preparation for deployment to Iraq. Focused training on communication, combat driving battle drills, small unit infantry tactics, force protection methods, gunnery and weapons used in theatre.

4/2006 - 5/2008 Texas Army National Guard El Paso, TX

Worked in conjunction with the US Border Patrol during Operation Jumpstart, stationed at a Border Patrol headquarters in El Paso, TX. Primary duties included data entry and trend analysis using Microsoft Office programs in the Border Patrol intelligence center for the El Paso sector of operations.

1/2002-1/2006 United States Army Fort Bliss, TX
Kunsan Air Base, Korea

Continuously trained on and maintained complex PATRIOT Missile System equipment - to include the radar set, engagement control station, antenna mast group, electric power plant, and launcher sets. I was assigned to both Fire Control and Maintenance sections, where I was recognized as a reliable and dedicated team member. Earned 4A and 4B certification as a soldier assigned to Fire Control, in addition to never failing an evaluation in March Order and Emplacement as a radar crew member and antenna mast group crew member. While assigned to System Maintenance, earned awards and recognition for quality upkeep and readiness in participation with Army-wide maintenance evaluations; contributing to my unit being named among the finalists for best in the Army in 2005.

SKILLS OVERVIEW

- Proficient in use of Mac OS X and all Windows platforms.
- Familiar with Microsoft Office suite.
- Effectual communication and writing skills.
- Competent with making presentations to small or large groups and comfortable with instructing others.
- Capable of evaluating a situation and able to make concise decisions.
- Able to maintain and organize a schedule without supervision.
- Limited use of forklift and other attachments on Bobcat skid steer loader.
- Safety oriented.

<u>AWARDS</u>

Army Commendation Medal
Army Achievement Medal (4)
Good Conduct Medal (2)
Iraqi Campaign Medal w/ Campaign Star
Korean Defense Service Medal
National Defense Service Medal
Armed Forces Reserve Medal w/ M Device
Army Service Ribbon
Overseas Service Ribbon (2)
Global War On Terrorism Service Ribbon
Combat Action Badge
Driver and Mechanic Badge (2)

References Available Upon Request